IHSAN KURNIAWAN

+6282114622053 / ihsankurn@gmail.com / https://ihsankurn.github.io/ihsan_portofolio/ / Depok, West Java, Indonesia

PROFILE

Bachelor's degree in Information Systems at Gunadarma University, with a GPA of 3.89/4.00. Prioritize work ethic, thoroughness, responsibility, and consistency in completing every job. Have some project experience in the field of data analysis. Have the ability to work together in a team, organized in work, competent, hardworking, adaptable, and good communication. Dedicated and highly motivated to develop professionally.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION SYSTEMS / GPA: 3.89

September 2020 - August 2024 / Gunadarma University / Indonesia

- Participating in the Independent Campus Program Learning Independent Student Exchange Bela Negara
- Joining the Independent Campus Program Independent Study of Data Analytics For Climate Change Resolution And Sustainable Development at Zenius

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROJECT-BASED VIRTUAL INTERN: BIG DATA ANALYTICS / KIMIA FARMA X RAKAMIN ACADEMY

November 2024 - December 2024

- Carry out various tasks related to big data analytics activities at Kimia Farma, including Data Analysis, Big Data Implementation, and Business Intelligence.
- Contributed to the management and analysis of big data to support strategic decision-making.
- Completed the Big Data Analytics internship program at Kimia Farma with an average grade of 85.16 (Highly Satisfactory).
- Developed skills in Data Analytics, Big Data Processing, and Scheduling during the internship program.
- Applied big data technology and methods to optimize operational efficiency and achievement of company goals.

SIB - DATA ANALYSIS FOR CLIMATE CHANGE RESOLUTION AND SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT / PT ZONA EDUKASI NUSANTARA (ZENIUS EDUCATION)

August 2023 - December 2023

- Collaborate with Product Manager and UI/UX team to develop green app prototypes based on early user feedback.
- Lead the team in the preparation of analytical reports to support data-driven decision making.
- Used data analysis to support green product development.
- Achieved "Honorable Mentions" award for Ecomart App final project that increased exposure of green products.
- Integrated sustainability principles in app design to support sustainability initiatives.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Dashboard Performance Analytics Kimia Farma Business Year 2020-2023 (December 2024)
- Game Trend Analysis Using Video Game Ratings Dataset (November 2024)
- Visualization of Sales and Profit Data by Product, Region, and Time (June 2024)
- Analysis and Visualization of Methane and CO2 Emissions Distribution in Indonesia (November 2023 December 2023)
- Explorative Data Analysis of Climate Change and Natural Disasters (August 2023)
- Customer Data Processing Using Microsoft Excel (March 2023)

.....

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATE

Certificate of Achievement - Big Data Analytics Project-Based Internship Program / Kimia Farma x Rakamin Academy (December 2024)

- Understand the concept of Data Warehouse and able to create Data Mart for focused data analysis.
- Learn Querying, Data Analysis, and Data Visualization to support data-driven decision making.
- Understand Data Storytelling and Dashboarding to deliver insights in an interactive and informative manner.

Data Analyst / BNSP (December 2024)

- Identify Data Management Needs for Business Processes.
- Collect Data, Analyze Data, Validate Data, and Determine Data Objects.
- Create Business Intelligence and Compile Analysis Reports.

Data Science & Data Analysis - BASIC DATA / MySkill (November 2023)

- Understanding Data & Business Process: Understand basic data and business process flow.
- Data Story & Dashboard: Building data-driven narratives and comparing dashboard functionality.
- Data-Driven Decision & Business Value: Using data to support decision-making and identifying business value from data.

Data Analytics For Climate Change Resolution And Sustainable Development / Studi Independen Zenius (August 2023 – December 2023)

- Learn data science, CRISP-DM, Python, and data visualization.
- Learn to create statistical models for data analysis.
- Learn SQL, dashboards, and business data science applications.

Data Preparation for Business / Gunadarma University (December 27-30, 2023)

- Identifying Data Requirements for Business Processes.
- Learn Collecting Data, Analyzing and Validating Data.
- Understand the Application of Data Preparation in the business world.

Data Analyst / DQLab (January 2023 – February 2023)

- Learn Python for Data Professional and SQL Fundamentals.
- Understanding Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) and Dataset Processing.
- Predictive Modeling Concepts and Proper Model Selection.

Basic Enterprise Resource Planning ERP Fundamentals / Gunadarma University (August 2021)

- Understand the basic concepts of Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP).
- Learn to use ADempiere, including purchasing and sales order processes.
- Mastering NAV technology, including purchasing, sales orders, and Bill of Materials (BOM).
- Familiar with SAP (System Application and Product in Data Processing) for data processing in business.

EXPERTISE

HARD SKILL

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- SQL, Python (Library: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Keras, Sklearn, Seaborn)
- Google Sheet, Power BI, Google Data Studio, Google BigQuery
- Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Descriptive Statistics, Correlation Analysis, Regression Analysis

SOFT SKILL

- Working with Teams and Individuals
- Time Management and Responsibility
- Adaptable and Communicative
- Detail, Innovative and Problem Solving

LANGUAGE SKILL

- Indonesia (Native)
- English (Basic)